<codelist name="TransactionType" date-last-modified="2020-10-28T16:50:18.905070+00:00" version="" xml:lang="en">
  <TransactionType>
    <code>1</code>
    <name>Incoming Funds</name>
    <language>en</language>
    <description>Funds recieved for use on the activity, which can be from an external or internal source. </description>
  </TransactionType>
  <TransactionType>
    <code>2</code>
    <name>Outgoing Commitment</name>
    <language>en</language>
    <description>A firm, written obligation from a donor or provider to provide a specified amount of funds, under particular terms and conditions, for specific purposes, for the benefit of the recipient. </description>
  </TransactionType>
  <TransactionType>
    <code>3</code>
    <name>Disbursement</name>
    <language>en</language>
    <description>Outgoing funds that are placed at the disposal of a recipient government or organisation, or funds transferred between two separately reported activities.</description>
  </TransactionType>
  <TransactionType>
    <code>4</code>
    <name>Expenditure</name>
    <language>en</language>
    <description>Outgoing funds that are spent on goods and services for the activity.</description>
  </TransactionType>
  <TransactionType>
    <code>5</code>
    <name>Interest Payment</name>
    <language>en</language>
    <description>The actual amount of interest paid on a loan or line of credit, including fees.</description>
  </TransactionType>
  <TransactionType>
    <code>6</code>
    <name>Loan Repayment</name>
    <language>en</language>
    <description>The actual amount of principal (amortisation) repaid, including any arrears. </description>
  </TransactionType>
  <TransactionType>
    <code>7</code>
    <name>Reimbursement</name>
    <language>en</language>
    <description>A type of disbursement that covers funds that have already been spent by the recipient, as agreed in the terms of the grant or loan</description>
  </TransactionType>
  <TransactionType>
    <code>8</code>
    <name>Purchase of Equity</name>
    <language>en</language>
    <description>Outgoing funds that are used to purchase equity in a business</description>
  </TransactionType>
  <TransactionType>
    <code>9</code>
    <name>Sale of Equity</name>
    <language>en</language>
    <description>Incoming funds from the sale of equity. </description>
  </TransactionType>
  <TransactionType>
    <code>10</code>
    <name>Credit Guarantee</name>
    <language>en</language>
    <description>A commitment made by a funding organisation to underwrite a loan or line of credit entered into by a third party. </description>
  </TransactionType>
  <TransactionType>
    <code>11</code>
    <name>Incoming Commitment</name>
    <language>en</language>
    <description>A firm, written obligation from a donor or provider to provide a specified amount of funds, under particular terms and conditions, reported by a recipient for this activity.</description>
  </TransactionType>
  <TransactionType>
    <code>12</code>
    <name>Outgoing Pledge</name>
    <language>en</language>
    <description>Indicative, non-binding advice of an intended outgoing commitment.</description>
  </TransactionType>
  <TransactionType>
    <code>13</code>
    <name>Incoming Pledge</name>
    <language>en</language>
    <description>Indicative, non-binding advice of an intended incoming commitment.</description>
  </TransactionType>
</codelist>
