<codelist name="ActivityDateType" xml:lang="en" complete="1" embedded="1">
    <metadata>
        <name>
            <narrative>Activity Date Type</narrative>
        </name>
        <description>
            <narrative>
            Types of date for activities.
        
            There are many different business models and dates that can be used
            to describe the start and end of activities. It is recommended that
            each publisher adopts their own consistent approach that provides
            users with a meaningful indication of the lifespan of an activity.
        </narrative>
        </description>
        <category>
            <narrative>Core</narrative>
        </category>
    </metadata>
    <codelist-items>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>1</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Planned start</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Début prévu</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>The date on which the activity is planned to start, for example the date of the first planned disbursement or when physical activity starts.</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">La date à laquelle on prévoit que l'activité commencera, par ex. la date du premier décaissement prévu ou la date où les activités concrètes commenceront.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>2</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Actual start</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Début réel</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>The actual date the activity starts, for example the date of the first disbursement or when physical activity starts.</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">La date à laquelle l'activité commence réellement, par ex. la date du premier décaissement ou la date où les activités concrètes commencent.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>3</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Planned End</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Fin prévue</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>The date on which the activity is planned to end, for example the date of the last planned disbursement or when physical activity is complete.</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">La date à laquelle on prévoit que l'activité prendra fin, par ex. la date du dernier décaissement prévu ou la date où les activités concrètes se termineront.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>4</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Actual end</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Fin réelle</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>The actual date the activity ends, for example the date of the last disbursement or when physical activity is complete.</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">La date à laquelle l'activité prend réellement fin, par ex. la date du dernier décaissement prévu ou la date où les activités concrètes se terminent.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
    </codelist-items>
</codelist>
